on July the 6th 2001 I remember it like
it was yesterday I had a visiting
delegation of Intelligence Officers from
the Middle East kofer black came along
with the chief of operations for the
Osama Bin Laden Group and they sit down
and cover starts and he says something
terrible is going to happen we're
picking up chatter with code
words where were you 911 happened I was
at CIA
headquarters um you know this the
story's kind of quaint now after all
these years and and all that has
happened over the course of all these
years um the on the morning of 911 I was
supposed to go to the White House with
uh kofer black who was the director of
the cia's counterterrorism center we had
a meeting scheduled with condalisa rice
who was the National Security adviser at
the time on a on an issue related to
Greek
terrorism and so um I got a call
at my desk uh saying that the driver was
uh was ready to take us down to the
White House so I walked over to Ker's
office to tell him that the driver was
ready and his secretary had a TV on her
desk now they're on every computer but
back then it was kind of unusual to have
a TV and she had a she had a TV on and
one of the towers of the World Trade
Center was burning and I said what
happened to the World Trade Center and
she said a plane flew into
it and I I naively said you know that
happened once before in
1932 a bomber flew into the Empire
estate building but it was really foggy
then it's so Crystal Clear today like
how can you not see that you're flying
into the World Trade Center and just as
I said those words the second plane hit
and then she turned to me I was standing
behind her she turned to me and she said
did you see that or did I imagine it and
I ran back to my office and I said guys
two planes just hit both towers of the
World Trade Center I think we're under
attack so everybody ran back up to the
front office now Ker's office had TVs
mounted above the door like CNN MSNBC
Fox BBC Russian Iranian whatever Chinese
and um and they were all starting to
switch over to a live
feed silence and I mean there were you
know 150 200 people just standing there
staring at the TVs in silence and then
finally somebody shouts will somebody
please lead and then kofer snapped back
into you know real life and said you uh
go to the director's office you go to
security you talk to this guy
you um finally a cop came in to the it
to the office and said we're evacuating
headquarters everybody get
out nobody budged and then an hour later
he came back and said if you don't
evacuate you'll be arrested which they
meant so I mean talk about
chaos we all
evacuated um I got about halfway home I
lived about I lived about five or six
miles from headquarters I got about
halfway and I just couldn't get any
closer to my place so I just abandoned
my car on the side of the highway um
my
then what was she girlfriend she became
my wife uh met me at my place we walked
to the roof of my building we watched
the Pentagon burn and um we tried to
donate blood but the lines were so long
we just couldn't wow and um and then I
said to her this is ridiculous we got to
get back to work so we walked back to my
car and I made a u-turn on the the
grassy me
and we went back to headquarters and
then I didn't leave headquarters for
another 4 days I just slept under the
desk and we got a bolt cutters and we we
cut the chain on the cafeteria doors and
we took all the food and cooked the food
and then laid it out on tables in the
hallway we ended up writing a check to
the Marriott for 10 or 15,000 bucks we
we stripped the place yeah yeah but you
know the story really begins a little
earlier than that I was working on on
Greek terrorism and on um
training
so on July the 6 2001 I remember it like
it was
yesterday I had a visiting delegation of
Intelligence Officers from the Middle
East and so my job was to welcome them
at the airport take them to their hotel
they get freshened up take them to CIA
headquarters they have a full day of
briefings we exchange gifts I take to
the director's office for a handshake
and a photo then I take him to uh uh a
steakhouse that night and then back to
the airport the next day so they come in
and I set up the full day of briefings
and I got some Junior analyst to come
and talk to us about Al-Qaeda I didn't
know anything about Al-Qaeda I was so
focused on European
terrorism so um this is 2000 2001 July
the 6th
so instead of this junior analyst coming
kofer black came along with the chief of
operations for the Osama Bin Laden
Group and I was like oh oh I said kofer
I said gentlemen this is Ambassador
kofer black he's the director of
counterterrorism for the CIA and this is
our chief of operations for the Osama
Bin Laden Group I was like so shocked to
see them
and they sit down and cover starts and
he says something terrible is going to
happen we don't know exactly what and we
don't know where but we know it's going
to be something on a scale that we've
never seen before he said we're picking
up
chatter with code words for a massive
attack the honey salesman is coming with
great quantities of honey there's going
to be a massive
wedding uh there's going to be a great
suck ER match they're all codes for an
attack he said we're hearing Al-Qaeda
Camp commanders talking to their
students and they're crying on the phone
and saying I'll see you in
Paradise so he said I beg you gentlemen
if you have any sources inside
Al-Qaeda please help us they all just
sat
there because they weren't focused on
Al-Qaeda either right
so at the end of the day I took him back
to the hotel there were a few hours we
had uh before uh dinner and I went back
to Ker's office to thank him and I said
kofer I got to ask you was that just for
their benefit or were you serious he
said oh I'm deadly serious he said
something terrible is going to happen I
said that briefing scared the hell out
of
me well that was July 6th September
11th it happens and I said to the there
was a guy I sat next to really great guy
I said this is what he was talking about
in July this is it the thing is is we
never expected it to happen here we
expected maybe another American Embassy
someplace a US military base a
hijacking we didn't expect they would
attack us right
here but they did and so literally
everything changed that day and it's
never returned to the pre- 911 with of
Life what's up guys thank you so much
for taking the time to watch the
interview um as you could probably tell
this is a brand new channel so if you
got anything out of this at all please
like the video leave me a comment tell
me what you thought tell me who you'd
like to see on the show um I see every
like I read every comment and I
appreciate all of it especially in the
beginning because as you know that kind
of support goes a long way on these
platforms so most importantly I have
some awesome guests coming up in the
future for interviews um so please
subscribe to the channel so you don't
miss any of them but again thank you for
your time appreciate the support and
hope to see you again soon